osho.com 2018-10-24

# Privacy Policy | OSHO | Meditation - Mindfulness and the Science of the Inner

**1.    INTRODUCTION  **   

This policy was created in order to demonstrate OSHO’s commitment to privacy and security, as well as to disclose all procedures related to information gathering and dissemination practices.

The following discloses information gathering and dissemination practices for the OSHO Website and its associated Media.

This privacy notice provides you with details of how we collect and process your personal data through your use of any OSHO resort visits, programs, services, products, applications, software, digital content (“Media”) and branded sites including [ www.osho.com](https://www.osho.com/), [ www.oshotimes.com](http://www.oshotimes.com/) and any branded OSHO sites linked from it (“Website”). “You” and “your” refers to you as an individual user of the Website or Media. 

By providing us with your data, you warrant to us that you are over 13 years of age.

OSHO Media International is the data controller and we are responsible for your personal data (referred to as “OSHO” “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice) 

Our full details are: 

OSHO Media International Ltd

Postal address: Waterfront Business Centre, No 5, Lapps Key, Cork, Ireland.

It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at [ support@osho.com](mailto:support@osho.com) or [ by clicking here to update your preferences](https://www.osho.com/read/newsletters/subscribe).

 **2\. WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU, FOR WHAT PURPOSE AND ON WHAT GROUND WE PROCESS IT  **

Personal data means any information capable of identifying an individual. It does not include anonymised data.

We may process the following categories of personal data about you:

(i) Communication Data that includes any communication that you send to us whether that be through the contact form on our website, through email, text, social media messaging, social media posting or any other communication that you send us. We process this data for the purposes of communicating with you, for record keeping and for the establishment, pursuance or defence of legal claims. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to reply to communications sent to us, to keep records and to establish, pursue or defend legal claims.

(ii) Customer Data that includes data relating to any purchases of goods and/or services such as your name, title, billing address, delivery address email address, phone number, contact details, purchase details and your card details. We process this data to supply the goods and/or services you have purchased and to keep records of such transactions. Our lawful ground for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps at your request to enter into such a contract. 

(iii) User Data that includes data about how you use our website and any online services together with any data that you post for publication on our website or through other online services. We process this data to operate our website and ensure relevant content is provided to you, to ensure the security of our website, to maintain back- ups of our website and/or databases and to enable publication and administration of our website, other online services and business. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to enable us to properly administer our website and our business. 

(iv) Technical Data that includes data about your use of our website and online services such as your IP address, your login data, details about your browser, length of visit to pages on our website, page views and navigation paths, details about the number of times you use our website, time zone settings and other technology on the devices you use to access our website. The source of this data is from our analytics tracking system. We process this data to analyse your use of our website and other online services, to administer and protect our business and website, to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and to understand the effectiveness of our advertising.  Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to enable us to properly administer our website and our business and to grow our business and to decide our marketing strategy.

(v) Marketing Data that includes data about your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences. We process this data to enable you to receive news, product information, event updates and to deliver relevant website content. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to decide our marketing strategy.

We may use Customer Data, User Data, Technical Data and Marketing Data to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you (including Facebook adverts or other display advertisements) and to measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve you. Our lawful ground for this processing is legitimate interests which is to grow our business. We may also use such data to send other marketing communications to you. Our lawful ground for this processing is either consent or legitimate interests (namely to grow our business).

 **Sensitive Data**

We do not collect any Sensitive Data about you. Sensitive data refers to data that includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data. We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

Where we are required to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of the contract between us and you do not provide us with that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract (for example, to deliver goods or services to you). If you don’t provide us with the requested data, we may have to cancel a product or service you have ordered but if we do, we will notify you at the time.

We will only use your personal data for a purpose it was collected for or a reasonably compatible purpose if necessary. For more information on this please email us at [INSERT EMAIL ADDRESS]. In case we need to use your details for an unrelated new purpose we will let you know and explain the legal grounds for processing.

We may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent where this is required or permitted by law.

 **3.   HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA **

We may collect data about you by you providing the data directly to us (for example by filling in forms on our site or by sending us emails). We may automatically collect certain data from you as you use our website by using cookies and similar technologies. Please see our [cookie policy](https://www.osho.com/cookie-policy) for more details about this.

We may receive data from third parties such as analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU, advertising networks such as Facebook based outside the EU, such as search information providers such as Google based outside the EU, providers of technical, payment and delivery services, such as data brokers or aggregators.

 **4\. MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS  **

Our lawful ground of processing your personal data to send you marketing communications is either your consent or our legitimate interests (namely to grow our business). 

Under the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations, we may send you marketing communications from us if (i) you made a purchase or asked for information from us about our goods or services or (ii) you agreed to receive marketing communications and in each case you have not opted out of receiving such communications since. Under these regulations, if you are a limited company, we may send you marketing emails without your consent. However you can still opt out of receiving marketing emails from us at any time.

Before we share your personal data with any third party for their own marketing purposes we will get your express consent.

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by [ clicking this link](https://www.osho.com/read/newsletters/subscribe) and checking or unchecking relevant boxes to adjust your marketing preferences OR by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or OR by emailing us at [support@osho.com](mailto:support@osho.com) at any time.

If you opt out of receiving marketing communications this opt-out does not apply to personal data provided as a result of other transactions, such as purchases, warranty registrations etc. 

 **5.   DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA  **

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below:

(i)   Service providers who provide IT and system administration services.

(ii)  Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers 

(iii) Government bodies that require us to report processing activities.

(iv) If OSHO is acquired by or merged with another company, in this event, OSHO will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy

We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

 **6.   INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS  **

We are subject to the provisions of the General Data Protection Regulations that protect your personal data. Where we transfer your data to third parties outside of the EEA, we will ensure certain safeguards are in place to ensure a similar degree of security for your personal data. As such:

(i) We may transfer your personal data to countries that the European Commission have approved as providing an adequate level of protection for personal data by; or

(ii) If we use US-based providers that are part of EU-US Privacy Shield, we may transfer data to them, as they have equivalent safeguards in place; or

(iii) Where we use certain service providers who are established outside of the EEA, we may use specific contracts or codes of conduct or certification mechanisms approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.

If none of the above safeguards is available, we may request your explicit consent to the specific transfer. You will have the right to withdraw this consent at any time. 

 **7.   DATA SECURITY   **

We have put in place security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used, altered, disclosed, or accessed without authorisation. We take technical, contractual, administrative, and physical security steps to protect personally identifiable information and associated systems. Where password access is required to access the Website or Media, you are responsible for keeping your passwords confidential. We also allow access to your personal data only to those employees and partners who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they must keep it confidential.

We are a global organisation and our data is held in secure locations all over the world, however we cannot guarantee that this information will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this policy. We have procedures in place to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach if we are legally required to.

 **8.   DATA RETENTION  **

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

When deciding what the correct time is to keep the data for we look at its amount, nature and sensitivity, potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure, the processing purposes, if these can be achieved by other means and legal requirements.

For tax purposes the law requires us to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they stop being customers.

 **9.   YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS   **

Under data protection laws you have rights in relation to your personal data that include the right to request access, correction, erasure, restriction, transfer, to object to processing, to portability of data and (where the lawful ground of processing is consent) to withdraw consent.

You can see more about these rights on the EU’s website [ here](https://ec.europa.eu/commission/priorities/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/2018-reform-eu-data-protection-rules_en)

If you wish to exercise any of the rights above, please email us at [ support@osho.com](mailto:support@osho.com) You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive or refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification when making such a request. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within 30 calendar days. It may take us longer if your request is particularly complex or if you have made more than one request. In this case, we will notify you.

If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the [Data Protection Commission in Ireland](https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Raise-a-Concern/1716.htm). Please contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.

 **10\. THIRD-PARTY LINKS     **

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We ensure that none of these are of an ‘adult’ nature. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site which OSHO advises you to review as we do not have any control over them. OSHO does not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy customs of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

 **11\. COOKIES   **

You can change your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please click to see our [ cookie policy](https://www.osho.com/cookie-policy). 

 **12\. PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and in our sole discretion. Your continued use of this Website after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.
